牢记
Remember...
我现在该怎么办？
What do I do with him now?
在你告诉我为什么要杀我之前不会让你死的
I won't let you die before telling me why you tried to kill me.
良心
Conscience.
你不能正视我吗？
You won't look me in the eye?
因为你离开了那份轻松的工作而去当了警察！
Because you left that cushy job and went and became a cop!
十年前，一户人家
It was ten years ago. A family came
搬进山上那间房子
and moved in to that house on the hill.
发生几起盗窃案
There were a few burglaries.
每个人都怪罪新来的人家
Everybody blamed the new family.
他们把房子烧了
They burned the house down.
我现在在这里找工作
I'm here now. Looking for a job...
这是我的简历
Here. Here's my resumé.
-你认识阿加·贝尤鲁吗？-他是我父亲
- Do you know Agah Beyoglu? - He's my father.
阿提斯，你不担心凶手会把你当作目标吗？
Ates, aren't you afraid at all that the murderer will target you?
就像他看着我一样
Just like he has his eyes on me,
我也在我家周围布置了眼线
I have my eyes on the perimeter of my house.
我要抓到那个凶手
I'm going to get that killer.
无论他跑到哪里，我都会找到他并逮捕他
Wherever he runs to. Wherever he hides. I'm going to find him, and arrest him.
今天是内芙拉的生日，我给她准备了一份礼物
TODAY IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY I GOT HER A BIRTHDAY PRESENT
你也变老了
You've grown older, too.
嗨 纳齐夫还记得我吗？
Hi there, Nazif. Remember me?
我是阿加
It's Agah.
来自坎布拉
From Kambura.
纳齐夫?
Nazif?
你好，纳齐夫
Hello, Nazif.
纳齐夫，你好吗？
How are you doing, Nazif?
暂停，在这里
Pause it. He's here.
他跳过了后篱笆
He jumped over the back fence.
那是什么？
What's that?
他穿的是什么？
What is he wearing?
是兔子吗？
Is it supposed to be a rabbit?
不，是猫
No. It's a cat.
看到它的胡须吗？
See its whiskers?
一只白猫
A white cat.
00:53
00:53.
你什么时候离开夜总会的？
When did you leave the nightclub?
大约01:30
Around 01:30.
你打给我的时候我正要走 我通常在01:00之前离开
I was just leaving when you called. I'm usually done by 01:00.
他一直在监视你
He was keeping tabs on you.
有一条路穿过树林，对不对？
There's a road that comes in through the woods, right?
是
Yes.
由于他不可能穿着那套服装上出租车
Since he couldn't have taken a cab in that costume...
当然也不能带尸体过来
With a corpse in tow, to boot.
他带着尸体自己开车来这里
He drove his own car here. Had the corpse with him the whole way.
一定有一部摄像机拍摄那条路
There must be a camera recording that road.
我们看一下
We'll see.
他是疯子
He's a lunatic.
你是谁？
Who are you?
谁？
Who?
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
你把尸体留在那里
You've left the body there. Leave.
一：拿一支红笔
One: Take a red pen.
二：
Two:
杀死纳齐夫
Kill Nazif.
三：
Three:
不要忘记
Don't forget the oud.
拿一支红笔，杀死纳齐夫，
Take a red pen, kill Nazif,
不要忘记
don't forget the oud.
如果纳粹不在家
If Nazif isn't home,
就饶他一命
spare his life.
是
Yes.
为什么他想确保它沉下去？
Why did he want to make sure that it sank?
-惊喜 -什么惊喜？
- It's a surprise. - What surprise?
他希望这是一个惊喜
He wanted it to be a surprise.
对不起，我不知道那是你的生日
Right. I'm sorry. I didn't know it was your birthday.
没事
Of course not.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
祝我生日快乐
Happy birthday to me.
他在做什么？
What is he doing?
休息
Resting.
不关心其他事 只是想躺一会
Not a care in the world. Just wants to lie down for a bit.
我回家了
I'm back.
你认为那具尸体是谁的，内芙拉？
Whom do you think the corpse belongs to, Nevra?
既然是礼物
Since it's a present...
一定是我一直在寻找的人
It must be someone I've been looking for.
我们现在干什么？
What do we do now?
我给局里打电话
I'll call the station.
犯罪现场小组很快就来
The Crime Scene Unit will arrive.
他们会看完这段录像，发现我在这里过夜
They'll go through this footage, find out that I spent the night here,
开始像躲瘟疫一样躲开我
and start avoiding me like the plague.
然后他们会问我们无数问题
Then they'll ask both you and I thousands of questions.
最后，他们会让我离开这个案子
And finally, they'll take me off the case.
并且让我辞职
Followed by my resignation.
或者
Or...
这些都不会发生
None of that will come to pass.
你删掉有我的镜头
You'll delete the footage I'm in.
我将那些贴纸从气球上撕下来
I'll rip those stickers off the balloon.
没有人会发现这是送给我的礼物
No one will find out that this was meant as a present to me.
你给155打电话
You'll call 155,
我会骗过大家
and I'll lie to everyone's faces.
一个接一个的谎言
Then another lie, then another.
谎言太多最后我都记不清了
I'll lie so much that I'll forget to remember them,
最终我还是会被发现
and I'll be found out sooner or later.
他们会对我感到失望，很可能将我辞退
They'll take me off the case, and I'll probably resign.
哪个听起来对你更好？
Which one sounds better to you?
-我们应该选哪个方案？- 内芙拉...
- Which one should we go with? - Nevra...
我有时对自己说
I say to myself sometimes...
我说
I say...
如果我从未决定要做警察怎么办？
What if I'd never decided to become a cop?
如果我没做过该怎么办？
What if I never did?
他会犯这些谋杀罪吗，
Would he be committing these murders,
还是因为我选择当警察才导致这些人死亡？
or are all these people dying just because I chose to be a cop?
看，你在那
See, there you are.
他还在这里
He's still here.
我不相信
I don't believe it.
我让你进屋的时候他还在这里
I'm letting you into the house, and he's still here.
他忘了拿包
He forgot the bag.
是杀手还是受害者？
KILLER OR VICTIM?
这就是为什么他把它留在这里
That's why he left it here.
你可以放大吗？
Can you zoom it?
你可以放大报纸吗？
Can you zoom into the newspaper?
记住……
REMEMBER. REMEMBER. REMEMBER. REMEMBER.
Remember...
记住？
Remember?
记住什么？
Remember what?
是给你的吗
Is it meant for you?
对你来说有什么特殊含义吗？
Does it mean anything to you?
这意味着只有一件事
It means only one thing.
他不是忘了拿包 他是忘了告诉我要记住
It's not the bag that he forgot. He forgot to tell me to remember.
-内芙拉...-怎么？
- Nevra... - Yes?
-确定吗？-现在确定了
- Are you sure? - I am now, Ates.
他们被杀是因为我是警察
They're being killed because I'm a cop.
不论他要我记住什么
And whatever it is that he wants me to remember,
他会一直杀人，直到我记住为止
they'll keep dying until I remember it.
请帮我接通犯罪现场调查组
Connect me to the Crime Scene Unit.
你要去哪里？还早呢
Where are you off to? It's still early.
我买了一些糕点 让我们吃早餐
I got some pastries. Let's have breakfast.
不行 爸爸 我要去上班了
I can't, dad. I got a job. I have to leave.
-什么工作？你之前的工作吗？-不，我晚点再告诉您
- What job? Your old one? - No. I'll tell you about it later.
-我走了-祝你好运
- I'm off. - Good luck.
-爸爸 -嗯？
- Dad... - Yeah?
今晚出去吃饭吧
Let's go out to dinner tonight.
冰箱里还有吃的
There's food in the fridge.
我知道
I know, not like that.
我想庆祝新工作
I want to celebrate the new job.
但是我有事要做
But I have errands to run.
除了那些填字游戏，你还有什么事？
What errands do you have other than those crosswords?
八点钟回家，我们一起去吃饭
Be home by eight and we'll leave together.
要去上学了吧？
School's started as well, huh?
-我不记得该怎么系了-我来吧
- I don't remember how to tie it. - I'll do it.
拿着这个
Hold these.
还有这个
And this.
-她在学校吗？-谁？
- Is she from school? - Who?
你的女朋友 她叫什么名字？
Your girl. What was her name?
-苏薇达 - 苏薇达 对了
- Suveyda. - Suveyda. That's it.
你知道这个名字的意思吗？
Do you know what the name means?
-还没好吗 -耐心
- No. Aren't you done yet? - Patience.
你就不想知道她的名字是什么意思吗？
You never wondered what her name meant?
我认为名字没有任何意义
I don't think names hold any meaning.
-为什么？-因为名字不是我们自己选的
- Why? - Because we don't choose our own name.
据说每个人
Each person
出生时心脏上都有黑色的印记
has a black mark on their heart when they're born, they say.
一旦他们找到自己的人生使命
Once they find their calling in life,
黑色的印记才会消失
only then does the mark fade away.
苏薇达就是那个黑色的印记的名字
Suveyda is what that mark is called.
还有另一种含义，但我不记得了
It does have another meaning, but it escapes me.
-算了 不打领带了 -等等！等等！
- Let's forget about the tie. - Hold on! Hold on!
让我想一想
I'm going to remember it.
意味着罪恶
It means sin. A hidden sin.
藏在心中的罪恶
The sin people hide in their chests.
深藏的罪恶
A deep, hidden sin.
你那里有深藏的罪过吗？
Do you have a hidden sin in there?
我有
I do.
-是苏薇达 -是的 当然了
- It's Suveyda. - Right. Of course.
-你呢？-当然了 有很多
- How about in yours? - Of course. In spades.
那就是了
There you go.
你准备好了
You're ready to go.
-谢谢-没问题
- Thanks. - No problem.
祝好运
Good luck.
辛苦了，内芙拉！
Good job, Nevra!
您终于抓住了凶手！
You finally caught the murderer!
您应该获得奖杯之类的东西
You should get a medal or something.
你睡着时他来找你
He came to you while you were asleep.
我想这跟你睡觉的地方有关
I guess it's a matter of where you sleep.
你需要睡在正确的床上，他才能来找你
You need to sleep in the right bed for him to come to you.
你收到了一个尸体快递
You got him delivered.
送货到家
Delivered to your address.
太好了！太好了！
Great! This is great!
内芙拉！你会为此付出代价
You'll pay for that, Nevra!
你会为此付出代价！
You'll pay for that!
回去工作！
Back to work!
你脑子有问题吗？
Are you sick in the head or something?
你不仅在所有人面前侮辱她
Not only do you try to belittle her in front of everyone at the scene,
然后还要投诉她？
and you do this! You're making a formal complaint?
你本来就是活该啊！
You deserved worse than you got!
-但是，先生 -闭嘴！
- But sir... - Shut the fuck up!
回去工作！
Get back to work!
阿提斯 阿尔巴伊 让我们谈一谈
So... Dear Ates Arbay. Let's get down to business.
这些文章的来源是谁
Who is your source for all these articles,
你给他们什么回报呢？
and what do you give them in return?
我什么都不给
I don't give anyone anything.
我有消息源
I have sources,
而且我也不必告诉你他们是谁
and I don't have to tell you who they are.
资料来源
Sources...
我明白了
I see. Alright.
你看 阿提斯 阿尔巴伊 这是很危险的交易
You see, Ates Arbay, this is dangerous business.
不论是谁向你卖消息
Whoever is selling you the case files
可能很快就会想要一些更珍贵的东西作为回报
might want something more precious in return very soon.
他们可能会变得贪婪 甚至可能会出卖你
They might get greedy. They might sell you down the river.
我怎么告诉你的？
What did I tell you?
跟随她的一举一动
Follow her every move.
无论她走到哪里都跟着她
Shadow her wherever she goes.
我不确定你是否真的听明白了
I'm not sure you're fully aware.
如果你做到了，我们现在就已经抓到凶手了
If you'd done your job, we'd have the killer by now!
长官，我可以说话了吗？
Sir, may I please speak?
快说
Go ahead, speak.
昨晚她去了妈妈的家
She went over to her mom's place last night.
阿诺尔在盯着她，他给我打电话请假
An?l was on her. He called me to ask what he should do.
-他的儿子病了，所以我让他回家 -真尼玛伟大
- His son was sick, so I let him go home. - Great fucking decision!
你不用再跟这个案子了，明白吗？
You're off the fucking case, alright?
塞法会接手
Sefa will handle it now.
带着你的投诉滚蛋吧！
And take that complaint and stick it up your ass!
-欢迎 -闭嘴
- Welcome. - Shut up.
你为什么对我生气？我们是同一战线的
Why are you mad at me? I'm on your side.
我叫你闭嘴
I told you to shut up.
-我为什么在这里？-不要说话
- Why am I here? - Don't speak unless spoken to.
我是受害者
I'm the victim here.
凶手来到我家，在我的花园里留下了尸体
The killer came into my home and left a body in my garden.
你还在这里审问我 你不应该出去找他吗?
Still, here you are, interrogating me. Shouldn't you be out looking for him?
你要怎么做？打我吗？
What are you going to do? Hit me?
打吧
Go ahead.
打我
Hit me.
阿提斯 阿尔巴伊
Ates Arbay.
在我的整个职业生涯中，我从来没有碰过这个房间里任何人的一根头发。
My whole career, I've never touched a hair on anyone's head in this room.
但是，如果你对案件有所了解并向我们隐瞒，
But if you know something about the case and are hiding it from us,
那我就一直揍你直到下周
then I'll knock you into the middle of next week.
还有一件事
And one more thing.
你跟我们不是一条战线的，阿提斯 阿尔巴伊
You're not on our side, Ates Arbay.
你知道你站在哪一边吗？
You know what side you're on?
在办公桌上搅乱他人生活的一面
The side where desk warriors mess with other people's lives.
那就是你的一面
That's the side you're on.
你知道我管那种人称为什么吗？
You know what I call the people on that side?
我称他们为小丑
I call them jesters.
我们在这里不给别人添乱
We don't mess with people's lives here.
相反 我们拯救他们的生命 明白了吗？
We save their lives instead. You got that?
我明白
I understand.
你认为他也是吗？
Do you think he does, as well?
带他出去 滚！
Get him out of here. Out. Out!
-一支红笔 -当然
- One red pen, as well. - Of course.
-胶带 -我已经给你了
- Duct tape. - I've already given you some.
还有一个
Another one.
-还有一些便签卡 -便利贴？
- And some sticky note cards. - Post-its?
不管叫什么 给我拿一些吧
Whatever they're called. Give me some.
坐下！
Sit down. Sit!
这一定是个玩笑！一定是！
This has to be a joke! It has to be!
-你是阿提斯 阿尔巴伊的消息来源吗？-不，先生
- Are you Ates Arbay's source? - No, sir.
-那是谁？-我不知道
- Who is it, then? - I don't know.
-他没告诉你吗？-他没有
- He didn't tell you? - He didn't.
你相信那个男人吗？
Do you trust that man?
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
今晚将举行新闻发布会
There will be a press conference tonight.
我们之前确定的凶手竟然不是凶手，人们一定会抓狂的
The killer turned out not to be the killer. Everyone's in a frenzy.
我要你出席记者招待会 不要去任何地方 现在出去。
I want you at the press conference. Don't go anywhere. Now get out.
-就是这样？ -就是这样
- That's it? - That's it.
您没有其他问题吗？
You don't have any other questions?
你在私人生活中犯的错误是你自己的事
The mistakes you make in your private life is your business.
只是不要在工作的时候犯同样的错误
Just don't make those same mistakes when you're at work.
你要把我调离这个案子吗？
Will you take me off the case?
内芙拉 出去
Nevra, get out.
等一下 这条线是谁的？
Wait a second. Whom did this belong to?
哎呀
Darn it.
看吧 红色好多了
See? Red's much better.
更具特色
More distinctive.
更醒目
Easier to see.
好了……
Alright...
这是什么？
What's this?
杀
KILL
这回就不会忘记了
I'll never forget now.
下午好，哈桑
Good afternoon, Hasan.
你不理我吗？
Won't you take my order?
塞利姆...
Selim...
-你好吗 -很好，你呢？
- How are you? - Fine, Vural. How about you?
-老实说，我不是很好 -那是为什么？
- I'm not great, to be honest. - Why's that?
你话太多了
You're talking too much...
我听说是你在多嘴
I hear you've been blabbering.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
告诉别人它萦绕在你的梦中
Telling people it was haunting your dreams.
跟别人谈论你的梦想有什么用呢？
What use is it, talking to people about your dreams, Selim?
你可能会出什么意外
Something might happen to you.
然后，当警察来问他们你发生了什么事时，
And then, when the cops come and ask them what happened to you,
没有人会说话
no one might feel inclined to talk.
最好不要说话
It's best if you didn't talk.
特别是内芙拉
Especially to Nevra.
你真的应该小心行事
You should really tread lightly.
塞利姆!
Selim!
阿姨 阿姨
Auntie! Auntie!
-让小伙子们帮你搬那些东西 -谢谢 乌拉尔
- Let the boys carry those for you. - Thank you, Vural.
-希望一切都好 -好
- Doing well, I hope? - Doing well.
有空来喝茶
Stop by for some tea sometime.
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Can I help you with anything?
不用了，非常感谢
I'm fine, thank you so much.
给你妈妈带个好
Say hi to your mom for me, though.
当然 你太客气了 祝你有美好的一天
Of course. You're too kind. Have a nice day.
兄弟，我能给你什么？
What can I get you, brother?
证据不足
MISSING SUSPECT
受害者
VICTIM
Victim.
-好了…… -托尔加，给我一点时间
- Now, boys... - Tolga, give me a moment.
内芙拉，我们已经知道这些谋杀案与你相关
Nevra, we already know that these murders have something to do with you.
这已经不是重名的问题了
This is not a matter of mistaken identity.
现在你也清楚了，凶手说的内芙拉就是你
You are the Nevra the victim is alluding you, as you know.
因此，根据制度
Since, as a matter of protocol,
我们不允许警察处理涉及他们自己的案件
we don't allow officers to work cases they're personally involved in,
我不想让你继续跟进这个案子
I didn't want you to take up the case.
你的上司也不想
Neither did your superior, Tolga.
假设凶手近期不会停止杀人
Suspecting that the murderer wasn't stopping anytime soon,
我请托尔加帮了个忙
I asked Tolga for a favor.
我请他让你继续处理这个案子
I asked him to keep you on this case.
因为你是我们唯一与凶手有关联的人
Because you were the only connection to the killer that we could find.
你仍然是
And you still are.
现在轮到托尔加要我帮个忙了
It was now Tolga's turn to ask me for a favor.
他让我和你说这些事情
He asked me to share all this with you.
但是我拒绝了
But I refused.
因为我的工作规则之一就是你不能相信任何人
Because rule one of my job is that you don't trust anyone.
如果凶手被抓
If the murderer getting caught
会泄露一些你不想泄露的秘密，
would expose some secrets you wouldn't want exposed,
我们必须找出它们可能是什么
we had to find out what they might be.
所以我们才瞒着你
That's why we kept you in the dark.
所以我们才会派人跟踪你
That's why we had you followed.
托尔加甚至告诉过你
Tolga even told you that
如果你就是贴纸上的内芙拉
if you were the Nevra from the stickers,
你会被调离这个案子
you'd be taken off the case.
我为什么现在要告诉我这一切，你可能很想知道
Why am I telling me all this now, you might ask.
因为我的工作第二条规则
Because rule two of my job
就是当某人值得信赖时
is to recognize when someone's trustworthy.
即使你很清楚你会被调离
Even though you knew fully well that you'd be taken off the case,
你仍然没有篡改证据
you still didn't tamper with the evidence.
生日快乐
Happy birthday, by the way.
我想你明白为什么所有这些诡计都是必要的
I assume you understand why all this subterfuge was necessary.
大家都知道
As you well know,
这是我国第一个如此大规模的屠杀案件
this is the first killing spree of this magnitude in our country.
这是例外情况
This is an exceptional case.
需要采取特殊措施
It required exceptional measures.
你现在都知道了
You know everything now.
选择权在你
The choice is yours to make.
你的上司和我都想让你继续跟进案子
Both your superior and I want you on this case.
但是如果你想远离这一切，我理解
But if you wanted to excuse yourself, I'd understand
做决定吧
Make a choice. Are you in or out?
-我当然要继续 -好
- I'm in, of course. - Good.
内芙拉...
Nevra...
不能再随随便便了
There's no more playing cowboy.
你将与塞法合作
You'll be partnering with Sefa.
每天都要向我汇报 明白了吗？
You'll be reporting to me every day. Are we clear?
明白 先生
We are, sir.
该死
Shit.
内芙拉和我秘密
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
那你们在这里做什么
What were you doing here, then?
-野餐 -只是野餐
- Out for a picnic. - Just out for a picnic.
野餐
Out for a picnic.
外国制造的 没有人能破解
Foreign-made. No one can crack it.
只需输入密码即可
Just pick a password and you're done.
注意不要忘记密码
Take care not to forget the password.
看？他们还把门破坏了
See? They tampered with the door also.
-如果您愿意，我能修好它 -不用了
- I can fix it if you'd like. - No need. It's fine.
有人闯入附近的一所房子
They broke into a house in the neighborhood.
当他们找不到任何可以偷的东西时，他们洗了个澡
When they couldn't find anything to steal, they took a bath.
-洗澡吗 -是的 对了 他们偷了一些花
- A bath? - Yeah. Oh, and they stole some flowers.
-他们偷花做什么？-我不知道 可能为了闻花香吧
- What would they do with flowers? - I don't know, smell them or something.
你一个人住吗？
Do you live alone here?
你为什么要问？
Why do you ask?
世界不再像过去那样单纯了
The world isn't as innocent as it used to be back in your time.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他们密切关注老年人
They keep tabs on old people.
不用担心 老人们也密切注视着他们
Don't you worry about that. Old people keep tabs on them, also.
我可以问你一个问题吗？
Can I ask you a question?
为什么修理工总是迟到？
Why are the mechanics always late?
什么？
Excuse me?
连环杀手调查中的谋杀嫌疑人图凡·埃利博尔
Tufan Elibol, the murder suspect in the serial killer investigation
被发现死于着名记者阿提斯 阿尔巴伊的花园中
was found dead in the back garden of famous reporter Ates Arbay's house.
该案似乎失控了
The case seems to be out of control.
为了减轻公众疑虑
Hoping to ease the public's concerns,
警察局计划今天某个时候举行新闻发布会
the police department is planning to hold a press conference sometime today.
您认为这有更深的含义吗？这两具尸体
Do you think this has a deeper meaning? Seeing two corpses
包裹在保鲜膜里？
wrapped up in cling film inside one day?
象征好运
It signals good fortunes.
您为什么认为他像这样打包？
Why do you think he packages them up like this?
他把图凡包装好，因为他是我的礼物
He packaged Tufan up because he was a present for me.
-所以他是出于礼仪吗？-是的
- So he follows protocol, you think? - Sure.
他一定是不想让动物吃掉这一具
He must not have wanted the animals to get to this one.
您是否认为他关心尸体被吃掉？
Do you think he cares about what happens to the bodies?
不是
No.
但他确实关心头上的标签
But he does care about the messages.
在我们看到之前，他不希望发生任何事。
He don't want something happen to them before we get the chance to read them.
内芙拉和我有个秘密
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
到处都有摄像头
They're everywhere.
我们聚集在这里庆祝土耳其工业的巨人
We are gathered here to celebrate a proud giant of Turkish industry,
这家拥有73年历史的公司
the 73-year-old company,
特兹吉德纺织公司
Tezgider Textiles,
与哈夫兰控股公司合并
merging with Havran Holding Company.
不，那句话太长了
No... That's too long a sentence.
-帮我改一下吧 -好的
- Edit it for me, will you? - Of course.
如果纳粹不在家，饶他一命
If Nazif isn't home, spare his life.
是谁呀？
Who is it?
我一定是走错了，对不起
I must have the wrong door, I'm sorry.
-阿加？是你吗？-是？
- Agah? Is that you? - Yes?
我是纳齐夫！你认不出我吗？
It's Nazif! You don't recognize me?
-纳齐夫？-等等
- Nazif? - Hold on.
-纳齐夫！-怎么可能？
- It's Nazif! - How's that possible?
来吧 亲爱的 进来吧
Come here, you heartbreaker. Come on, come on in.
等等
Wait...
真的是您，阿加！多久没见了？
It's really you, Agah! How long has it been?
已经二十年了 可能更长
Must've been twenty years. Maybe even more.
阿加...
Agah...
亲爱的
Darling...
别紧张
You don't need to feel threatened.
是我，纳齐夫！
It's me, Nazif!
事实上，我改名为纳兹已经16年了
Actually, I've been going by Naz for 16 years,
不过你叫我什么都可以
but you can address me however you feel comfortable.
梅布鲁雷还好吗，我希望她很好
So? How's Mebrure? She's well, I hope.
梅布鲁雷不幸过世了
Mebrure passed away, sadly.
十年前
Ten years ago.
噢 亲爱的
Oh, dear.
愿她安息
May she rest in peace.
她是一个如此美丽的女人 她有一颗纯洁的心
She was such a beautiful woman. She had a pure heart.
来脱掉那件外套
Come on, take off that coat.
坐下来，舒服点
Sit back, get comfortable.
没事的，纳兹先生
This is fine, Mr... Naz.
我们之间不需要互相称呼先生和太太
We don't need to call each other mister and missus.
这是好个消息 纳兹
That's good to hear, Naz.
-我母亲也去世了，阿加 -愿她安息
- My mother's passed on, as well, Agah. - May she rest in peace.
你以前来过这所房子吧？
You'd been to this house before, right?
您被派往伊斯坦布尔后，我们来拜访过您
We came to visit you after you were assigned to Istanbul.
是的，我记起来了 现在我已经退休了
Yes, I remember now. I left that job, as you know.
我知道
I know.
从那以后我们再也没有见面了
We haven't seen each other since.
是的
Yes, we haven't...
阿加...
Agah...
好了
Come on.
看着我
Look here.
看着我的眼睛
Look into my eyes.
我还是我 阿加
That's better. I'm the same person, Agah.
我是你的老朋友 好吗？
I'm your old friend. Alright?
这是为了……
It's for...
我有皮肤病
I have a skin condition.
医生说必须要涂护手霜
I have to wear a cream. Doctor's orders.
-希望你快点好起来-谢谢
- I hope you get better. - Thank you.
阿加，我有个主意
Agah, I have an idea.
我们吃点烤面包吧
Let's have some raki!
记者将会有无数个问题
The reporters will have a million questions.
我们得把故事讲清楚
We have to get our story straight.
内芙拉，梳理一下案情
Nevra, wrap the case up for me.
最后一名受害者的名字是萨利赫·古登 51岁的卡车司机 没有前科
The last victim's name was Salih Guden. No priors. 51 years old. Truck driver.
内芙拉...
Nevra...
从最开始说起
From the beginning.
刑事法院的穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔法官
Mehmet Yurtgil. Judge. Heavy penal court.
他因受贿而出名，但我们没有证据
He had a reputation for taking bribes, but we have no proof of it.
纳伊姆汉·图雷迪
Naimhan Turedi.
他是一个酒馆里的歌手
He's a man that sung at taverns.
没有前科
No priors.
但是我和纳伊姆汉有一些共同之处
But Naimhan and I share something.
坎布拉.
Kambura.
他来自坎布拉，一直住在那里直到20岁
He's from Kambura. Lived there until he was 20.
我的家人也住在坎布拉
My family lived in Kambura, as well.
我妈妈在邮局工作
My mom worked at the post office.
我九岁时就被分配到坎布拉
She was assigned to Kambura when I was nine.
我们在那里呆了一年，直到她被分配到另一个城市
We stayed there for a year, until she was assigned to another town.
我从没回过坎布拉
I never went back to Kambura,
但是我妈妈非常喜欢那个城镇，以至于她退休后就搬到了过去
but my mom loved that town so much that she moved there after she retired.
-在那儿结婚 -您不必说这些
- Got married there, in fact. - You don't have to mention that.
然后是图凡
And then, there's Tufan.
图凡与坎布拉没有任何联系
Tufan has no connection whatsoever to Kambura.
但是，在穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔法官被杀之前三天，
However, three days before Mehmet Yurtgil was killed,
阿迪坎法院大楼被烧毁
the Ard?chan Courthouse was burned down.
那是他拿到枪的地方
That's where he got the guns.
他还带走了他在证据柜里能找到的所有非法物品
He also took whatever illegal items he could find in the evidence locker.
他可能拥有毒品和爆炸物
He could be in possession of drugs and explosives.
我们还在等着看他到底有什么东西
We're still waiting on the inventory list to know exactly what he took.
为什么选择阿迪坎法院大楼？
Why the Ard?chan Courthouse?
我无法理解 为什么不是另一个法院而是那个呢?
I can't wrap my head around that. Why not another courthouse but that one?
没关系 继续
Nevermind. Keep going.
他还带走了法院案卷
He also took the case files in the courthouse.
他需要有人来顶罪
He needed someone to pin the murders on.
必须是一个有前科的人
He had to be someone with a record
以便我们能够迅速将他确定为杀手，
so that we'd quickly identify him as the killer,
为真正的杀手赢得时间去实施其他的谋杀
buying the real killer time to commit the other murders.
他从这些案卷中找到了图凡 一名前诈骗犯 因杀害妻子而入狱
He found Tufan from those case files. An ex-con jailed for killing his wife.
他可能在烧毁法院后绑架了图凡
He probably kidnapped Tufan after burning down the courthouse,
把他的指纹贴在贴纸上
and planted his fingerprints on the stickers.
顺便说一下
By the way...
我们在图凡尸体的贴纸上没有发现指纹
The stickers and the card we found on Tufan bore no fingerprints.
-那么这位刑事法官 -穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔.
- Now, this heavy penal judge... - Mehmet Yurtgil.
是的
Yes.
他和坎布拉有任何联系吗？
Does he have any connections to Kambura?
没有，先生，到目前为止我们至少没有找到
No, sir. At least none we've found so far.
第三位受害者 卡车司机萨利赫·古登呢？
How about the third victim, Salih Guden, the truck driver?
他不是来自坎布拉
He's not from Kambura,
但他已经去那里工作了多年了，所以，他可能有联系
but he's been going there for work for years. So yes, he might.
那好吧
Alright, then.
除去图凡之外 三名受害者其中两人来自坎布拉
Three victims. Scratch Tufan. Two of them are from Kambura.
你已经在坎布拉住了一段时间了 那算是个线索，对吗？
You've lived in Kambura for a while. That counts as a lead, don't you think?
所以这一切都与坎布拉有关
So all this does have something to do with Kambura.
但是为什么他杀死了图凡？
But why did he let Tufan go?
他为什么要我们找到图凡？
Why did he want us to find Tufan?
一定是帖木儿 他正在对图凡做尸检
That must be Timur. He's doing the autopsy on Tufan.
-发现什么了吗，帖木儿？-整个身体都被漂白剂浸透过了
- Do you have anything, Timur? - The whole body was soaked in bleach.
他身上没有DNA的痕迹
No traces of DNA on him.
但是他的手腕和脚踝有软组织创伤
But he does have soft tissue trauma on his wrists and ankles.
他被绑了很长时间
He was kept tied up for a prolonged time.
我不知道这是否意味着什么，但他们喂猫粮给他吃
And I don't know if it means anything, but they fed him cat food.
我发现他肚子里有猫食
I found cat food in his stomach.
嫌犯
SUSPECT
这怎么可能？
How is this possible?
我真的不知道
I really had no idea.
我尽我所能不让你们知道
I did everything I could to keep it from you guys.
你以前和女人交往过，是吗?
You've been with women before, haven't you?
我有 但很难不去怀疑真实的感受
I have. It's really hard not to doubt your true feeling.
太可怕了 感觉好像你的整个世界都要塌下来了
It's so scary, it feels like your whole world might come down.
这就是为什么我一直试图说服自己
That's why I always tried to convince myself
我的感觉不是真实的
that what I was feeling wasn't real.
这是一种欺骗自己的方法，真的
It's a way of deceiving yourself, really.
我和很多女人上床只是为了向别人证明自己
I went to bed with so many women just to prove myself to others.
但我又不能和任何人上床
It's not like I was able to have sex with any of them, though.
有一个女孩
There was this one girl...
她很漂亮 我不记得她的名字了
She was beautiful. I can't remember her name. Whatever.
那个混蛋桑古尔曾经给她拉皮条，还记得吗？
That bastard Sungur used to pimp them out, remember?
我记得
I do.
她哭了，一想到我不喜欢她，她就受不了
She cried. The thought of me not liking her was devastating for her.
她以为我会回去告诉桑古尔我不喜欢她
She thought I'd go back to Sungur and tell him I didn't like her.
她很害怕他会殴打她
She was scared he'd beat her up.
其实我回想起来
Actually, when I think back...
她是我曾经告诉过的第一个人
She was the first person I ever told.
她是我第一个坦白的人
She was the first person I confessed to.
我告诉她我不是很喜欢女人
I told her I didn't really like women.
这就是我的故事了
That's all I have for you. My story ends there.
是时候讲讲你的故事
Time to tell yours.
你怎么来这里了？
What brings you to my home?
纳齐夫...
Nazif...
抱歉，纳兹
I'm sorry, Naz...
你说得真好听！
You say it so beautifully!
再说一次我的名字
Say my name again.
纳兹
Naz...
-怎么了，亲爱的--我病了
- Yes, dear? - I'm sick.
早期阿尔茨海默氏症
Early stages of Alzheimer's.
可悲的是我会忘记一切
Sadly... I'll forget everything.
一切
Everything.
所以我告诉自己
So I told myself...
在我忘记之前
That before I forgot...
我应该去拜访我的老朋友
I should visit my old friends.
-天啊 -是的
- Oh, dear. - Yeah.
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
阿加...
Agah...
你知道我们现在要做什么吗？
You know what we're going to do now?
你还记得那天晚上我们喝醉了吗
Do you remember that night when we got drunk
一起写歌
and wrote a song together?
嗯？
Yes?
-我还留着呢 -不会吧
- I still have it on paper. - No way.
你看
See?
真了不起 那是塞加的琴键吗
That's really something. It was in the key of Segah?
不，不是塞加！
No, not Segah!
阿加...
Agah...
在阿加的琴键上
It's in the key of Agah.
我这里有乌德琴
I have the oud right here.
没有更多的夜莺 没有更多的玫瑰
No more nightingales No more roses.
内心充满了痛苦
The pain inside Is all I have
我不能再继续了
I can't go on Any longer.
哦，爱人，爱人，请终结我
Oh, lover, lover, Please end me.
我不能再继续了
I can't go on Any longer.
哦，爱人，爱人，请终结我
Oh, lover, lover, Please end me.
啊
Ah...
唉
Alas...
在阿加的琴键上
In the key of Agah...
我浪费了生命
I wasted my life...
我发疯了！
I've gone mad!
疯了！
Gone mad!
-我们曾经有过很多欢乐 -那些日子
- We used to have so much fun. - Those were the days.
我们曾经背诵过，叶海亚·凯末尔的诗
We used to recite poems. From Naz?m, from Yahya Kemal...
-为那段日子欢呼 -过去的岁月欢呼
- Cheers to those days, Agah. - Cheers to young times past.
闭嘴！我们还年轻！
Shut up! We're still young!
当然，这是第几杯了？
Sure we are. How many glasses does this make?
我好醉
I'm pretty drunk.
我好久没见到你了！别抱怨
I haven't seen you for ages. Stop whining!
你知道我的想法吗？
You know what I thought?
我以为一旦成为??女人
I thought that once I became a woman,
我所有的烦恼都会消失 最终会很高兴
all my troubles would go away. I'd finally be happy.
我确实变得快乐
I did become happy.
但是我忘了一个细节
But I'd forgotten about a detail.
有些东西不见了，阿加
Something was missing, Agah.
你不能活在没有爱的世界中
You can't live without love.
当你没有爱时 什么都不能做
Nothing works when you don't have love.
没有爱，
Without love,
没有更多的夜莺
no more nightingales...
没有更多的玫瑰
No more roses.
我很难过，阿加！
I'm so unhappy, Agah!
我好寂寞！
I'm so alone!
多年来没有人敲过那扇门！
No one's knocked on that door for years!
但是我不在乎，我仍然每晚都打扮！
But I don't care! I still dress up every night!
终于奏效了，您终于来了！
It works, you see? You finally came!
你来这里我真的很高兴
It was so good of you to come!
也许你不是来说再见
Maybe you didn't come to say goodbye.
也许你来打个招呼！
Maybe you came to say hello!
一只小鸟告诉我
A little birdie told me...
你无法摆脱你过去的某些东西
That there's something about your past that you just can't shake.
可能是我吗？
Might that be me?
你有一滴
You have a drop...
葡萄酒在那里
of raki right there.
让我喝个够
Let me drink my fill.
那是谁的诗？
Whose poem is that?
我的
Mine.
为你而作
For you.
阿加
Agah...
什么
What the...
该死！
Shit!
这是什么？
What's this?
你做了什么，阿加？
What did you do, Agah?
你做了什么！
What did you do!
去死吧，你这个混蛋！
Die, you bastard!
过来！
Come here!
别！
Don't!
别打坏乐器！
Don't hurt the instrument!
不要！不要！
Don't! Don't!
别！
Don't!
别
Don't...
去死吧！
I'll show you!
这就是所有的信息 我已经总结了一下现在的情况
That's all the information I have for you. I have summed up the situation for now.
未来几天我们将继续与公众分享我们的信息
We will keep sharing our information with the public in the coming days.
最后，对于住在伊斯坦布尔附近的公民来说，
Lastly, for our citizens who live in Istanbul's immediate vicinity,
没有理由惊慌 我们正在处理这起案件
there's no reason to panic. We are on the case.
虽然主要是凶杀科
Chiefly the Murder Bureau,
但实际上整个警察部队
but in fact the whole police force,
都正在努力解决谋杀案 并迅速将凶手绳之以法
is working to solve the murders and bring swift justice on the murderer.
我们的公民可以安心
Our citizens can rest easy.
无论是谁犯下这些谋杀案
Whoever it is that is committing these murders
很快就会被抓住
will soon be caught and tried.
您不必怀疑
You don't need to doubt that.
我很快就能回答大家的提问
I'll be taking questions shortly,
但是，正如您所知，这种情况涉及敏感信息，
but since the case, as you know, involves sensitive information,
我可能不得不避免回答您的一些问题
I might have to refrain from answering some of your questions.
敬请谅解
I ask for your understanding.
先生 先生
Sir! Sir!
-继续 -扮成猫有什么特殊含义吗？
- Go ahead. - Does the cat costume signify anything?
-你认为这可能是个线索吗？-他绝对很喜欢动物
- Do you think it might be a message? - He's definitely an animal lover.
但是众所周知，希特勒爱上了他的狗 还有其他问题吗？
But as you all know, Hitler was in love with his dogs. Any other questions?
你知道！
You do realize!
你已经在那里呆了一个小时没说有用的话
That you've been up there for an hour without saying anything.
一个星期内有四人被杀
Four people were killed inside a single week.
人们由于害怕而离开家乡
People are scared to leave their homes.
而你却只能说……
And all you have to say...
为了减轻公众的恐惧
To allay their fears...
你正在处理了
Is that you're working on it.
所有聚集在这里的记者和数百万电视观众都知道
As all the reporters gathered here and the millions watching on TV know,
一名政府官员说他正在处理
a government official saying he's working on it
表示他们什么也没做
means they are not doing anything.
如果您正在取得任何实际进展，请与我们分享
If you were making any real progress, you'd have shared that with us.
你的努力没有任何成果
You have nothing to show for your efforts.
阿提斯 阿尔巴伊，对不对？
Ates Arbay, right?
你说完了吗？
Are you done?
好
Good.
大家聚集在这里
Gathered here...
有数不清的记者有着一尘不染的记录
are countless reporters with spotless records.
我将尊重他们对你工作合法性的看法
I will defer to them on the legitimacy of your work.
但我谴责您诽谤我和我部门的言论
But I condemn you for your words that defame me and my department.
你真的什么都没有吗？
Do you really not have anything?
你没有线索吗？
Don't you have any leads?
请冷静一下！我明白你们担心什么
Please calm down! I get it, you're concerned.
你有权利这样做
And you have a right to be.
这就是为什么我要与您分享其他信息的原因
That's why I'll be sharing another information with you.
谋杀嫌疑犯利用图凡·埃利博尔来摆脱我们的追踪
The murder suspect used Tufan Elibol to throw us off his trail.
但是图凡·埃利博尔的尸体包含了有用的证据
But Tufan Elibol's body contained useful evidence.
你逼我的，阿加！
You made me do it, Agah!
图凡·埃利博尔，凶手曾经用他来迷惑我们
Tufan Elibol, whom the killer used to throw us off his scent
将对杀手的抓捕有帮助
will prove instrumental in the killer getting caught.
凶手已经插翅难逃
The killer has made his bed.
炸弹爆炸，炸死50人，你没有惊慌
A bomb goes off, killing 50 people, and you don't panic.
但是，当人们被一个人接一个杀掉的时候，你就惊慌了吗？
But when people are picked off one by one, then you do. Is that it?
我们确定的是杀人犯不会折磨受害者，对吗？
One thing we know is that the killer doesn't torture his victims, right?
到目前为止还没有
He hasn't so far, yes.
爸爸，我们在这里！
We're over here, dad!
-塞米尔？-看看我带来了谁
- Cemil? - Look who I've brought.
-我告诉过你他会认出我 -过来！
- I told you he'd recognize me. - Come here!
我在电视，报纸上到处都能见到你 我当然能认出你
I see you all over on TV, in newspapers. Of course I recognized you.
-你现在真的是自己的人了 -你没变！
- You're truly your own man now! - You haven't changed a bit!
-我变老了 -我假装没听见 你看起来好极了
- I'm getting old. - I won't hear it. You look incredible!
我变老了
Come on. I'm getting old.
你们怎么认识的？
How do you know each other?
我最近才见到祖哈尔 从今天开始 她为我工作
I've met Zuhal really recently. As of today, she works for me.
你没告诉我
You didn't tell me.
我真的很爱他，你知道我很小的时候就认识他
I really love him, you know. I knew him as a child, back in Kambura.
真是个惊喜！
Such a nice surprise!
-嗨，顺便说一句 -嗨
- Hi, by the way. - Hi.
真是个惊喜！
Such a nice surprise!
你好吗，塞米尔？
So? How are you doing, Cemil?
他似乎没有表现出
He seems to exhibit
连环杀手的偏执和性幻想
none of the obsessions and sexual fantasies of serial killers.
我们不知道他是否喜欢杀人
We don't know whether he enjoys the act of killing or not.
他似乎是一个很简单的凶手
He seems to be a simple murderer.
他们通常只有两个动机：金钱或报仇
They usually have only two motives: Either money or revenge.
既然他从未拿取财物，那么他一定是想报仇
Since he's never stolen anything, he must be after revenge.
他要找很多人报仇，这使他成为连环杀手
He has so many people to take revenge on that it turns him into a serial killer.
不只是三四个人
Not just three or four people.
可能有10个
Maybe ten...
也许20个
Maybe 20.
甚至更多
Maybe even more.
然后有消息
And then there're the messages.
都是为了我
All meant for me.
我的意思是
I mean...
他为警察留下了线索
He leaves clues for the police.
但为什么？
But why?
他为什么要这样做？
Why does he do it?
十年前，有一群人，我不知道有多少人，
Ten years ago, a crowd, I don't know how many people yet,
聚集在这所房子外面，并烧毁了它
gathered outside this house and burned it to the ground.
您是怎么知道的？谁告诉您的？
How did you find out about this? Who told you?
我妈妈的现任丈夫塞利姆告诉我的
Selim, my mom's current husband told me.
可悲的是他曾经也在这里
He was here too, sadly.
塞利姆说，有一个人把火把扔了进去
Selim says that a single person threw the torch,
但他没看到是谁
but he never saw who.
但据我所知，没有人进去帮助里面的人
But from what I gather, no one ran in to help the people inside.
那天晚上，七人在大火中丧生
That night, seven people died in the fire.
一位母亲，一位父亲和五个孩子
A mother, a father, and five children.
最重要的是，至少根据塞利姆所说
And most importantly, at least according to Selim,
那天晚上其中一名受害者就在人群中
one of the victims was in the crowd that night.
纳伊姆汉
Naimhan.
你跟我说过的那个人
The man you told me about,
你一直在这里寻找的那个人
the one you chased all the way here...
-你没看过他的脸吗？-不，我看不到！
- You never saw his face? - No, I couldn't!
当时太黑了
It was dark.
我没见过他的脸，但我确定他想把我带到这里
I never saw his face, but I'm certain that he wanted to bring me here.
他把我带到这里，要我记住
He brought me here, and asked me to remember.
我在这里三年了 这是我第一次听说
I've been here for three years. This is the first I'm hearing of this.
真奇怪，你从来没想过为什么会这样吗？
That's strange. You never wondered why and how it happened?
没有
No.
真不错
Good for you.
打开电脑 我想看看档案
Turn on the computer. I want to take a look at the archives.
嗯
Um...
嗯？
Um?
档案在这里
The archives are in here.
过去三年来你一直在做什么？
What have you been doing for the past three years?
等待分配到另一个城镇
Waiting to get assigned to another town.
去那边等一下，过来 内芙拉
Go wait over there, then. Come on in, Nevra.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
他是一个谦虚的人
He's such a humble man.
我们已经聊了好几个小时，他从没提到过
We've been talking for hours, and he hasn't mentioned
他曾经做过的一切
all he's done even once.
我做了什么？
What have I done?
别害羞
Don't be coy.
我九岁就是孤儿了，祖哈尔
I was orphaned at the age of nine, Zuhal.
我父亲突然去世了
My father died suddenly.
我母亲是个不幸的人
My mother was a wretch.
她也总是生病，让我们一个人呆着
She was always sick, too. We were left all alone.
你知道谁照顾我们吗？
You know who took care of us?
坎布拉照顾我们
Kambura did.
坎布拉的人们
Kamburans.
他们给我买了学习用品
They bought me school supplies.
给我衣服穿
They dressed me.
即使是他们中最穷的人也能找到办法给我妈妈弄点钱
Even the poorest among them found a way to get my mom some money.
他们都希望我学习知识，所以我做到了
They all wanted me to become learned. So I did.
如果不是他们的话，我绝对不会来伊斯坦布尔上大学
I could've never come to Istanbul to go to college if it weren't for them.
还有你的父亲
And your father here,
为我付了家教费
paid for a tutor for me,
虽然他只是一个公务员
even though he was just a civil servant.
你年复一年地为我的导师付费
You paid for my tutor year after year.
好了，别说了
Come on, forget about it.
-任何人都会做相同的事 -不
- Anyone would've done the same. - No.
我从未忘记，阿加
I've never forgotten, Agah.
我要归功于坎布拉和你
I owe a lot to Kambura and to you.
你什么都不欠我的
You don't owe anyone anything.
你无法想象我发现祖哈尔是你的女儿时我有多高兴
You can't imagine how happy I was when I found out that Zuhal was your daughter.
但是我现在以祖哈尔为证人告诉你，
But I'm telling you now, with Zuhal as my witness,
如果您需要任何帮助，我希望您告诉我
that if you need anything at all, I want you to tell me about it.
如果你不这样做，我会很伤心的
I'll be deeply hurt if you don't.
当然会的
Sure. Of course. I will.
我很认真 你知道我是认真的
I'm serious. You know I mean it.
我知道
I know.
你是好人
You're a good man.
你在那时是好人
You were back then,
现在也是
and you still are.
杀
KILL
内芙拉，我找到了
Nevra, I found it.
什么？
What?
你有报告吗？
You have the reports?
内芙拉，没人烧毁它
Nevra, no one burned it down.
什么意思，没人？
What do you mean, no one did?
这是报告 起火的原因是香烟
Here's the report. The cause for the fire was a cigarette.
屋子里有两个煤气灯，这就是大火失控的原因
There were two gas lamps inside the house. That's why the fire grew out of control.
但是外面有一群人
But there was a crowd gathered outside.
是的 警方报告是这样的：
Yes, they did. It's written in the police report.
“当地人聚集在房子周围
"The locals gathered around the house"
在消防部门到达之前尽了最大的努力来控制火势
and did their best to control the fire before the fire department arrived.
但是，尽管有当地人的努力，
However, despite the locals' efforts,
屋子里的七个人，当时大概睡着了，
the seven people inside the house, probably asleep at the time,
无法被救出”
"were unable to be rescued alive."
内夫拉，那些人没有聚集在那里放火
Nevra, those people didn't gather there to start a fire.
他们聚集在那里是要救出里面的人
They gathered there to rescue the ones inside.
但是塞利姆告诉我的不一样
But Selim told me otherwise.
他在那里 亲眼所见
He was there. He saw it with his own eyes.
不，我当时不在
No. I wasn't there at the time.
可是塞利姆
But Selim,
你告诉我的 你朝房子扔石头
you told me you threw a stone at the house.
你告诉我它萦绕在我的梦中
You told me it haunted your dreams.
只是梦而已
Exactly. It's nothing but a dream.
他混淆了梦和现实
He confuses them with reality.
他不按时服药就会这样
He goes off the rails when he neglects his meds.
他们大老远从伊斯坦布尔赶来，希望发现一些线索
They came all the way from Istanbul hoping to find something.
你应该再考虑一下
You should be more thoughtful.
Sugar?
加糖吗？